前面我们学习了style,以及怎样把它们
Earlier we learned about styles and
应用到某一个别的视图
how you can apply them
to an individual view.
如果你希望把它应用到整个app或者activity的所有视图
If you want to apply it to all the views
in an activity or application,
你可以在manifest中的activity或者application标签里
you can do it by specifying a theme
attribute on the activity or
指定一个theme属性
application tag in the Android manifest.
现在我们使用style来调整action bar 使main activity与
Now we style the action bar to look
like these visual mocks for the main and
detail activity看上去像我们设计的样子
detail activity.
settings activity是一个特殊的情况，因为它继承自
The settings activity is a special case
because it extends from the preference
PreferenceActivity类，而不是ActionBarActivity
activity class,
instead of the action bar activity.
所以那些在下一节再讲
So that's going to be
done in the next section.
对于这两种情况，我们希望背景色都是
For both cases here we want
the background color to be this
十六进制蓝色
blue hex color.
我们注意到detail activity只显示了标题，没有图标
We notice that the detail activity
only shows the title, no app icon.
这个按键是返回到父activity的
And this button is to go
up to the parent activity.
如果你看到哪个视图有图标，或者
If you see visual marks
that have the app icon or
一个不同的向上按键，他们都过时了
a different up button,
they are outdated.
material design是我们的新容貌
The material design,
this is our new look.
另一方面，main activity展示了logo
On the other hand,
the main activity shows the logo.
它和app图标不是一个属性
It's a different attribute
than the app icon.
它在这节课的早前就有了
And this was provided in an acid
drop earlier in the lesson, and
叫做ic_logo
it's called ic_logo.
因为这些不同之处，我们需要两个不同的主题
Because of these differences,
we need two separate themes.
我们为 detail activity使用AppTheme，为main activity使用ForecastTheme
We use AppTheme for the detail activity
and ForecastTheme for the main activity.
在material design里，你可以选择一些颜色
In material design you can
choose several app colors and
并且在theme里指定它们来丰富你的UI组件
specify them in your theme to
colorize certain UI components
他们都受框架层的约束
that are controlled by the framework.
比如框架层会使用colorPrimary作为actionBar
For example the framework will use
colorPrimary as a background of your
或者Toolbar的背景
action bar or your tool bar.
框架层也会使用colorPrimaryDark作为
The framework will also
use colorPrimaryDark
status bar的颜色
as the status bar color.
为了定制我们的主题，打开vaules文件夹下的style文件
To customize our app theme, go to
the Styles file in the values folder.
我们的AppTheme继承自系统的亮色主题
Our AppTheme inherits
from the system Theme for
因为我们有一个带有DarkActionBar的亮色内容区
a Light app because we have a Light
content area with a DarkActionBar.
我们指定colorPrimary作为sunshine_blue的颜色
We specify colorPrimary to
be this sunshine_blue color.
它将会显示在action bar上
And this will be displayed in
the action bar, also known as at bar.
然后设置colorPrimaryDark为暗色
And then we set the colorPrimaryDark
to be this darker color.
它将会显示在  status bar上
This is going to be
shown in the status bar,
典型的，status bar会比app bar拥有更暗的颜色
and typically the status bar is
a darker color than the app bar.
这些颜色 都定义在 colors.xml 文件里了
Both of these colors are defined in
the colors.xml file as seen here.
然后为 main activity创建一个主题
Then for the main activity,
we create a ForecastTheme.
我们继承自AppTheme，因为它有很多我们希望添加到这的属性
We inherit from AppTheme in case
there's more attributes that we want to
那么我们免费继承过来
add here, and
then we'll inherit them for free.
但是我们要重写actionBarStyle
However, we do override
the actionBarStyle.
这是为了我们可以设置logo，指定到drawable文件中
This is so that we can set the logo
to point to this drawable file and
也可以改变displayOptions，这样logo就出现了
also change the displayOptions so
that the logo does appear.
更多displayOptions的信息
For more information on
the action bar displayOptions,
你可以看一下这个列表
you can see the list here.
如果你现在运行app
If you run the app now,
在actionbar下面默认会有一个阴影
there's a shadow below the action
bar that is default behavior.
但是为了视觉的一致，我们希望actionbar
However, according to our visual
designs, we want the action bar and
和today项在同一平面有蓝色的背景
the today item with the blue
background to be on the same plane,
这意味着我们不想要这个阴影盖在另一个上面
meaning we don't want one to
cast a shadow over the other.
结果是我们设置actionbar的elevation为0
As a result we set the action
bar elevation to be zero
如果它是单窗格模式的话
if it is in one pane mode.
如果是两个窗格模式。那么today项不需要有一个专门的背景
If it's in two pane mode, then the today
item does not have a special background,
actionbar有阴影也是可以的
and it's fine if the action
bar casts a shadow.
快去撸吧
Go ahead and make these changes
now using the gists provided.